- [Narrator] Being a React developer means
that you should know
about good software design and architecture.
As a React developer,
your responsibilities are to design
and implement the UI components of a web application
by using good software practices.
And your job is to provide and deliver clean code
that is maintainable and scalable.
As easy as it sounds,
being a good React developer requires
expertise in many areas, such as project organization,
software testing and quality assurance,
performance and optimization,
and also state management.
What is state management?
State management is the implementation of a design pattern
to synchronize the state of your application
throughout all the components of your application.
Indeed, application state management is crucial
in software developments.
And as your applications grows in size and complexity,
it is time to think beyond the basics.
And learning to manage the state effectively becomes
critical for every project.
For any development team,
the goal is to pick the right state management solution
and the techniques that works for your needs.
And this is what makes the difference between clean code
and code which is difficult to maintain and understand,
infamously known as spaghetti code.
And so effective state management is key
for building robust and maintainable software systems.
And understanding how to effectively manage
the state of your application is essential
to software and web development.
This course is not just about teaching state management,
but also to show how to choose the right solution
and help you build large-scale applications
that are quality-driven, highly maintainable,
easy to test and to scale.